paylocity.com 2019-05-23

# View Our Privacy Policy | Paylocity

## Disclaimer

All statements, information, and data given herein are believed to be accurate and reliable, but are presented without guarantee, expressed or implied. Statements or suggestions concerning possible use of our products, including but not limited to the design of Paylocity products and systems, are made without representation or warranty that any such use is free of patent infringement, and are not recommendations to infringe any patent. The user should not assume that all safety measures are indicated, or that other measures may not be required.

Paylocity is committed to protecting online user privacy. In order to ensure your privacy, information Paylocity collects through our website at www.paylocity.com (“Site”) is used only in the manner and for the purposes described in this Paylocity Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy.”)

## Newsletter Disclaimer

Paylocity provides information in e-newsletters for general guidance only, and does not constitute the provision of legal advice, tax advice, accounting services, investment advice, or professional consulting of any kind. The information provided herein should not be used as a substitute for consultation with professional tax, accounting, legal, or other competent advisers. Before making any decision or taking any action, you should consult a professional adviser who has been provided with all pertinent facts relevant to your particular situation.

Tax articles in e-newsletters are not intended to be used, and cannot be used by any taxpayer, for the purpose of avoiding accuracy-related penalties that may be imposed on the taxpayer. The information is provided “as is,” with no assurance or guarantee of completeness, accuracy, or timeliness of the information, and without warranty of any kind, express or implied, including but not limited to warranties of performance, merchantability, and fitness for a particular purpose.

## User Consent to Privacy Policy

Any person accessing, browsing, or otherwise using the Site, either manually or via an automated device or program, shall be considered a “User.” All Users are bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. Users consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of personally identifiable User information (“Information”) pursuant to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## Information Collected from Users

Paylocity collects the email address of Users that email a question or comment to Paylocity or submit a customer review.

Paylocity collects the billing and shipping addresses, including relevant e-mail and phone information. This includes users who register to become Paylocity members or enter any Paylocity contests or other promotional features available on the Site.

Through the use of “cookies” (for more information regarding cookies, see below), Paylocity may collect and store anonymous information relating to Users’ browsing patterns, including, for instance, the User’s browser version, site referral information, IP address, operating system, and other technical Site use information.

## Cookies

The Site uses a feature of Internet web browsers called a cookie, which is a file that a User’s web browser places on a User’s computer’s hard drive, to assign an identification code to the computer and to collect anonymous browsing information. On this Site, cookies are used in conjunction with session variables to track a User’s shopping cart and expire as soon as an order is completed or if a shopping cart sits idle for a lengthy period without being checked out.

Paylocity does not use cookies to retrieve Information about Users from a User’s computer unless the User knowingly and willingly provided such Information. For instance, Paylocity’s cookies do not collection any Information and the cookies do not collect, store or contain any credit card information.

You may set your Internet web browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to prevent cookies from being sent. If you prevent a cookie from being sent, you may limit the functionality Paylocity can provide you when you visit the Site, especially when purchasing an item on the Site.

## Limited Collection & Use of Information

Paylocity does not collect data indiscriminately. Paylocity collects personal information only for the purposes of providing and promoting the services we offer and limits use to those purposes, including initiating, maintaining, enhancing, and terminating the employee-employer relationship. Personal information shall be collected by fair and lawful means, and not by misleading or deceiving individuals about the purpose for which information is collected.

Paylocity uses the Information collected from its Users to:

  * Respond to Users’ questions or comments;
  * Administer a User’s contest entry or entry in other promotional feature;
  * Fulfill a User’s purchase request and notify Users of their order status; and
  * Provide Users with important functionality changes to the Site, new Paylocity services, and special offers we think you will find valuable.

Paylocity may also collect personal information from other sources, either with the consent of the individual or where permitted or required by law. Examples of indirect sources of personal information include background checks, employers or personal references.

## Aggregate & Anonymous Data

Without limiting the confidentiality, data protection and intellectual property rights terms set forth in this Privacy Policy, Paylocity has a perpetual right to use aggregated, anonymized, and statistical data (“Aggregated Data”) derived from the operation of the software or services (“Services”) provided to users, and nothing herein shall be construed as prohibiting Paylocity from utilizing the Aggregated Data in the provision of its Services or for operating purposes.

## Retention & Disposal

Paylocity retains personal information only as long as necessary to fulfill the stated purposes or as legally required and thereafter appropriately disposes of such information. Paylocity will specify minimum and maximum retention periods for the various records containing personal information.

When personal information is no longer necessary or relevant for the identified purpose or to fulfill a legal or business requirement, it shall be securely destroyed. Paylocity will either physically or electronically erase the personal information or make it anonymous in a non-recoverable manner.

## Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

Unless we have your consent or except as required or permitted by law, Paylocity will not sell, share, trade, or give away any Information that it collects or receives regarding its Users.

Paylocity may disclose information about our Users to others if we have a good faith belief that we are required to do so by law or legal process, to respond to claims, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Paylocity or others. Paylocity may disclose Information to a third party in the event that a third party acquires Paylocity or its assets. (See Sale or Acquisition section below.)

Paylocity may share information about you with third parties in certain circumstances including in the following situations:

**Affiliates** – Paylocity may share information with companies that we own or control, that are owned or controlled by us, or that are under common ownership or control.

**Blogs, Online Postings, and Testimonials** – Paylocity may decide to allow users to share comments, postings, testimonials, or other information. If you choose to submit such information to us, the information that you submit may be available generally to the public. Information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

**Business Transition** – In the event that Paylocity, or any portion of our assets, are acquired, we may share all types of information with the acquiring company.

**On-line Applications & Tools** – Paylocity may offer tools, widgets, or applications on our website, such as search engine functionalities, that are powered by third parties. If you use those applications or tools, any information that you provide may be shared with the third party that provides that functionality. The third party’s use of that information is subject to their privacy notice.

**Law Enforcement** – Paylocity may report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we reasonably believe to be unlawful, or that we reasonably believe may aid a law enforcement investigation into unlawful activity. In addition, we reserve the right to release your information to law enforcement agencies if we determine, in our sole judgment, that either you have violated our policies, or the release of your information may protect the rights, property, or safety of Paylocity, or another person.

**Legal** **Process** – Paylocity may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. This also includes sharing your information with governmental entities, or third parties in response to subpoenas, court orders, other legal process, or as we believe is necessary to exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims that have been brought against us, or to defend against possible legal claims that we determine in our sole discretion might be brought against us.

**Partners** – Paylocity may share information with other companies that provide products or services that we think may be of interest to you.

**Service Providers** – Paylocity may share information with companies or individuals that provide us with services. These services may include, among other things, providing products or services to you on our behalf, creating or maintaining our databases, researching and analyzing the people who request information from us, preparing and distributing communications, or responding to inquiries.

**Linked Websites** – Our website, our emails, or our application may link to third parties’ websites. The Site may provide hyperlinks, which are highlighted words or pictures within a hypertext document that, when clicked, take you to another place within the document, to another document altogether, or may take you to a third-party website not controlled by Paylocity. These hyperlinked third-party websites may collect and disclose Information different than this Site. Paylocity is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of information collected through these websites, and Paylocity expressly disclaims any and all liability related to such collection, use, or disclosure. It is also possible that third parties’ websites or emails may link to our website. Paylocity is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by third parties, and information collected by third parties is not governed by Paylocity’s privacy notice.

If Paylocity has knowledge that a third party uses or discloses personal information in an unapproved manner, Paylocity takes reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure.

Where applicable, to limit or opt out of the disclosure of personal information, individuals should contact their employer or Paylocity in the manner set out in the Enforcement section.

## Children

The Paylocity Site is not directed toward children under 18 years of age, and Paylocity does not knowingly collect any information from children under 18 years of age through the Site.

## Security

Paylocity has a variety of security measures and controls in place to protect the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information that we collect and to secure your personal information from accidental loss unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. To learn about our security controls, please visit our [Security](https://www.paylocity.com/about/security/) page.

## Access

Unless Paylocity is permitted or required by law to prohibit access, Paylocity makes personal information available for review and updating, either directly through the self-service feature in its products, by directing individuals to the employer for access, or through an access request made to established contacts within Paylocity.

Paylocity responds to requests within the time limit set out by the applicable privacy legislation and, if applicable, provides the individual with an estimate of the cost associated with administering and responding to the request. Paylocity requires sufficient information to authenticate requests for access.

## Sale or Acquisition

In the event that another company acquires Paylocity or all or part of its assets, we reserve the right to include Information among the assets transferred to the acquiring company.

## Applicable Law/International Issues

Information that is submitted to this Site will be collected, processed, stored, disclosed, and disposed of in accordance with applicable U.S. law. If you are a non-U.S. User, you acknowledge and agree that we may collect and use your Information, as discussed above, outside your resident jurisdiction. In addition, such Information may be stored on servers located outside your resident jurisdiction. U.S. law may not provide the degree of protection for Information that is available in other countries. By providing us with your Information, you acknowledge that your have read this Privacy Policy, understand it, agree to its terms and consent to the transfer of such Information outside your resident jurisdiction. If you do not consent to the terms of this Policy, please do not use this Site, but if you have already provided us with Information, please contact us and let us know how you would like us to handle such information.To learn about Paylocity and the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), [click here](https://www.paylocity.com/2018/05/11/ensuring-compliance-european-general-data-protection-regulation/).

## Accountability & Enforcement

Paylocity complies with applicable United States, international, and local data protection laws and regulations worldwide governing the privacy and protection of personal data that is collected, processed, transferred/exported, organized, altered, used, disclosed, combined, destroyed, and held, including adherence and commitment to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Paylocity has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. Paylocity is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Paylocity commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Paylocity at: [privacy@paylocity.com](mailto:privacy@paylocity.com).

Paylocity has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship.

It is possible, under certain conditions more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, for an individual to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

## Onward Transfer

Paylocity reserves the right to employ other companies and individuals as our subcontractors or vendors to perform functions on our behalf. All such contractors are contractually obligated to use and maintain the confidentiality of personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Paylocity shall be liable in accordance with all applicable laws if found to have willfully violated consumer’s rights in the onward transfer of personal data to third parties.

## Amendments to Privacy Policy

Paylocity reserves the right, at any time, to modify, alter, or update the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy without prior notice. Modifications shall become effective immediately upon being posted on our website. Your continued use of the website after modifications are posted constitutes an acknowledgement and acceptance of the Privacy Policy and its modifications.
